Hello.
For this task we are supposed to decide for
all these terms down here whether they are
correct according to the operation declared
for the vector graphics domain in the lecture.
I don't really have the space here to put
the definitions next to this task.
Because either way the definitions or the
task would be too small for you to read.
So, I am just going to assume you have the
definition opened on the side.
Or that you thoroughly studied them ahead
of time.
For each incorrect term, I am going to explain
what the problem is.
And mark the problematic area.
Which is also what you should do.
And for the parts that are correct, we don’t
need to do anything.
Except that they are correct.
And then, we can move on to the next one.
So, in the first term we have a print statement
with another print statement inside here.
And if we look at the definitions for print,
we know that print expects something of type
string, which print does not provide.
So, this print in here is an incorrect argument
for the outer print.
Because the type does not match.
For B we have a “move” which expects something
of type Picture and 2 more parameters,
determining by how much it is moved.
And here we have a print("no") composited
with “circle” which returns
something of type Picture.
So, the first argument here is correct and
the second and third argument are -2
and 5 which are also correct and acceptable
here.
So, B is correct, we can just put a little
check mark next to it marking it as correct
and move on to C. In C we have “scale”
and the obvious thing to always check for
these here is the type and number of arguments
that we have here.
And here we have the first argument which
is long rotate here which returns something
of type Picture, which is correct for the
first argument.
Then, we have a 3.2 which is correct for the
second argument, a 6 which is correct for
the third argument.
But here, we have a fourth argument and
scale only expects 3 arguments.
So, this extra argument here is incorrect.
And makes this term incorrect.
Moving on to D we have another “scale”
inside of which we have a “move” which
goes up to the closing parenthesis down here.
This is all of the type Picture.
So, this is correct for the first argument.
And we have 2 more arguments, no superfluous
arguments here.
So, this outer scale at least is correct.
So, moving further inside we have this “move”
which expects something of type Picture, which
this “color” here provides.
And provided by how much it is moved by, this
is the number and type of arguments for move
as well.
So, we can step further inside.
And here, we have “color” which the first
argument that is “blue”, which is not
correct.
Because the first argument needs to be of
type Picture for “color” operation which
this second argument provides.
So, this “rotate” here, which is correct,
provides the “picture” and blue provides
the color.
So, these are just the wrong way around which
makes this term incorrect.
Moving on to E we have a “rectangle” with
the correct type and number of arguments.
Creating something of type Picture for the
composition operator here as the first argument
which is correct.
And we have “rotate” with a “rectangle”
inside and by how much it is rotated creates
something of type Picture as well which is
correct for this composition operator second
argument again.
So, this entire first part here is correct.
And for the second composition our operator
expects something of type Picture at first
which this first composition operator provides.
And another “picture” which this “circle”
provides as well.
So, E is correct.
It is not what I wanted to do.
This is correct.
And we can move on to F. F gives us a “rotate”
with a “rectangle” being rotated.
Here we have to watch out for the parentheses,
where they are.
So, this is the first argument here, this
entire “rotate” thing which is correct.
For this composition operator.
So, this is something of type Picture.
But there is something of type Picture inside
and the correct arguments here.
And back here we have “move” this goes
all the way till the end.
This is our second argument for this composition
operator also of type Picture, “scale”
provides the first argument of type Picture
which is correct for “move”.
And 2 more arguments that are of type Float,
by how much it is moved, so this outer
“move” here is correct, we can step further
inside, this “scale” expects something
of type Picture which “print” provides
and by how much it is scaled.
So, “scale” is correct as well.
And we only need to look at “print” now.
And “prints” expects something of type
string as we have learned in the first part,
which this “Modellierung” is not.
Because it is missing it is not marked as
being a “string “. So, this “Modellierung”
here is not a “string” and therefore not
a correct argument for “print”, making
this term incorrect.
For G, once again have “rotate” at the
start.
And here we have to pay attention to the parenthesis
again.
Because this composition is inside of this
“rotate”.
So, this “move” here crossing the composition
operator, all of this is the first argument,
up to the last comma back here.
So, this is the first argument providing something
of type Picture.
Because we have a “move” here.
And then, we have a Float back here
that 64 which provides by how much it is rotated
by.
So, the outer “rotate” has the correct
arguments.
Now, we can step further inside, we can look
at “move” which gets something of type
Picture provided by this composition operator
and this “scale” here.
This whole thing here from “circle” till
the end of here is the first argument of “move”.
And we have 2 more parameter telling us- oh
sorry, all the way up to here even.
All the way up to this parenthesis here.
So, we have from “circle” up to this 6.2
closing parenthesis, being the first argument
being of type Picture.
And then 2 more parameters telling us how
much it is moved by which are the correct
type.
So, this “move” is correct and we can
step further inside.
This “circle” is pretty easy.
This is correct.
This creates something of type Picture for
the composition operator.
And the second argument here is “scale”
up to the closing parenthesis which is something
of type Picture and has the correct arguments.
“Rotate” creates something of type Picture
and 2 more Floats here for determining how
much it is scaled by.
This is correct.
This “rotate” needs something of type
Picture which the circle(5) provides
and by how much it is rotated by so this is
correct as well.
Now we step this far deep inside here as we
could everything is correct.
So, term G is correct as
well.
Put a check mark here, marking G as correct.
And finally, we have H with an outer “rotate”
this “rotate” gets, as the first parameter,
something of type Picture which starts by
this “scale“ here, up to this last comma
back here.
This is the entire first argument, something
of type Picture which is correct.
And the second argument is correct as well.
Telling us how much it is rotated by.
So, this outer “rotate” is correct and
we can step further inside.
This first argument, like I said, it goes
from here to back over here.
This is one long “scale”, inside of “scale”
there is something of type Picture this “move”,
together with the composition operator and
something else is being scaled.
And the second argument telling us the X axis
of the scaling.
But we are missing a third argument for the
scale which would be the Y axis of scaling.
So, we are missing an argument here.
I cannot really mark this here correctly.
I am just drawing in here a little bit.
So, basically, we do not need to look any
further inside.
Because this already tells us this term is
incorrect because this “scale” here is
incorrect.
And that finishes the task.